Srikanth Perumandla (1) Featured

Software Engineer seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, Solution Architecture, Performance Tuning, Core Java, J2Ee, Maven, Spring, JUnit



Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 3 Month(s) Current Designation: Software Analyst

Current Company: PurpleTalk Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: software engineer, software development, application programming, core java, spring boot, spring

security,eureka,mysql,microservices,junit,maven,jpa,json,aws,redis,hibernate,spring batch,Jenkins,Docker,Apache kafka

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 6-Jan-21 Last Modified: 6-Jan-21

Summary

4+ years of experience in Java Technologies.

Excellent development skills using CORE JAVA, J2EE, SPRING BOOT, SPRING SECURITY, AWS cloud, Web Services (RESTFUL), JSON, JUNIT, GitHub, Devops(docker), IOT, Maven, Apache Kafka.

Extensive Object Oriented Development OOP/OOD experience.

Good working knowledge on Application development and maintenance life cycle process.

Adapted and institutionalized many disciplined, organized, and progressive methods and ways to plan, prioritize, and accomplish tasks assigned.

Strongly skilled and experienced Software Developer with a proven talent for spotting opportunities for innovation. Having hands on experience in handling Use Cases, Functional Specification, Knowledge Transfers and Business Analysis. Aided team members and colleagues in analyzing the right tools, and in organizing and scheduling and designing sites for clients based on specific requests.

Work Experience

PurpleTalk as Software Analyst Feb 2020 to Till Date

IBASEIT as Software Engineer

Jan 2018 to Feb 2020

Project Name Credit Union360 Duration Mar 2019 to till date

Team Size 8 people, completed

Client Credit Union

Description Credit union360 is a chargeback system where the middle-level bank will interact with credit union360 to provide service to customers. Customers will use credit union applications to post there quires future discussion will happen with credit union360 executive and management. Customers can raise their chargeback for their transactions request to respective banks using credit union360. It acts as an intermediate layer between the customer and the bank. Chargeback alerts are given to customers from credit union360 on bank feedback.

Role & Contribution

Setting up creditunion project environment & development.

Maintained and deployed in production environment

Creating development environment in AWS cloud

Maintaining the data base setup.

Technologies Core java, Spring Boot, Web Services (Restful), AWS cloud

Platform Windows 10

Project-2

PUSHINNOVATIONLIVE Duration Jan 2018 to Feb 2019 Project Name

Team Size 10 people, completed

Client **Push Innovation Live**

Description It is project which contains multiple E-commerce CRM?s em? into single system, provides services through IVR System. And store complete data information of limelight & konnektive in pushlive live system to support customers through orders related quries. Pushlive contains multiple CRMs operational behavior, means its supports all individual crm actions.it creates platform for multiple E-commerce CRM?s.

Role & Contribution

Setting up pushlive project environment

Maintained and deployed in production environment

Creating development environment in AWS cloud

Maintaining the data base setup.

Core java, Spring Boot, Web Services (Restful), AWS cloud Technologies

Platform Windows 10

L&T Technology Services as Software Developer

Oct 2016 to Nov 2017

Project Name THALES(Repair Management Tools) Duration Apr 2017 to NOV 2017

20 people, completed Team Size

THALES

Description It is project which consists repair details of flight, Modules like Main Admin, Analytics Engineer, Product Support Engineer, and Repair Station Engineer. Where admin is to allocate analytics, product and repair station engineer. Analytics engineer should provide access only to ANALYTICS. Product Support Engineer should provide access only to REPAIR FUNCTIONS & ANALYTICS functionality. And Admin should provide access to REPAIR MANAGE, REPAIR FUNCTIONS & ANALYTICS functionality.

Role & Contribution Setting up the environment.

Setting up Thales project environment

Adding functionality of TLS server

Maintained and deployed in production environment

Running project with Jboss Server

Maintaining the data base setup.

Technologies Core java, Spring, Jboss, Web Services (Restful)

Platform Windows, Linux 16.04

Project-4

Project Name Tele2 Car Insurance (IOT). Duration OCT 2016 to Apr 2017

Team Size 4 people, completed

Tele2 Jasper

Description It is simple SIM management system which works on IOT (internet of things).the main agenda of the application is to fetch the status of any electronics devices which has been inserted the SIM by the provider it gives the chance for the user to set the time (or) timer. So, that he will get the regular updates from the devices and vice versa.

Role & Contribution Setting up the environment.

Service Side API's were implemented

Developed restful API's for Frontend

Generating Ng-Rock API's

Maintained and deployed in production environment

Deployed war in server

Created Docker images for war files

Technologies WebServices(RESTFULWebServices), Docker, Apache Tomcat

Platform Windows, Linux 16.04

OTG technologies as Software Trainee

Jun 2015 to Feb 2016

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
CORE JAVA, J2EE , Web Services			
Spring Boot, SPRING SECURITY, JUNIT			
GitHub, Devops(docker), IOT,Maven			
spring boot			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
MySQL Eclipse, Microsoft Office			
Windows Family, Linux 16.04			
SPRING BATCH		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
hindi	Proficient			
english	Expert			
Telugu	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No